# ZAID ISMAIL SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Durban, South Africa | P: +27828965760 | zaidismail031@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/zaid-ismail-0957a61b1

**GitHub:** https://github.com/zaid-ismail031 **Personal Website:** https://zaidismail.co.za

### **ABOUT ME**

Organized, detail-oriented STEM graduate with experience in videogame programming and web development. Strong written and verbal communication skills. A quick learner and a great problem solver.

**Skills:** Python, C, C++, JavaScript, C#, Unity (Game Engine)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## ThoroughTec Simulation

Junior Software Developer

Jan 2023 - Present

- Developed training simulators for surface and underground drill-rigs using the Unity game engine.
- Handled both 2D-related and 3D-related gameplay programming, working on both the various vehicles' GUI's and the vehicles' abilities to tram and drill/bolt holes.
- Cultivated a solid skill set in OOP and event-driven programming.

# **Multiple Projects**

Open-Source Contributor on GitHub

Aug 2022 - Present

- Refactored code in the Xenia Xbox 360 emulator project, written in C++.
- Contributed to the documentation of Scrapy, a Python web-scraping framework.
- Refactored code in DevilutionX, a source port of the action role-playing videogame Diablo and its expansion Diablo: Hellfire.
- Replaced icons on the frontend of Oppia, Google's open-source education platform.

#### **Tau Space**

Operations Engineer

Sep 2022 – Dec 2022

- Wrote applications to directly interface with 5G network infrastructure.
- Developed test cases for network applications.
- Handled daily monitoring of servers, databases and business operations.
- Worked with databases to generate on-the-fly insights about business and systems operations.
- Automated several monitoring processes (such as querying databases, checking log files and generating CSV files) using Python.
- Liaised with clients in the South African telecoms industry to support day-to-day business and systems operations.

#### FORMAL EDUCATION

# University of KwaZulu-Natal - Durban, South Africa

Jan 2017 - Dec 2021

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (with Honours), Civil Engineering

- Completed eight Mathematics courses involving calculus, linear algebra, mathematical systems and statistics.
- Completed a dissertation on the flood attenuation function of artificial wetlands, which required data analysis and mathematical modelling.
- Planned the construction of a structural steel warehouse for the course's final design project.

Stanford Online Jun 2022

Machine Learning

 Learned and applied several machine learning concepts including supervised learning, unsupervised learning, linear regression, logistic regression, gradient descent, neural networks and the SVM (support vector machine) algorithm.

• Implemented machine learning algorithms using Octave, a high-level programming language that is specialized for numerical computation and linear algebra.

Harvard Online Mar 2021

CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript

- Gained proficiency in creating web applications using Django.
- Created interactive web pages using JavaScript.
- Learned how to use HTML5 and CSS.
- Built a stock trading web application, utilizing a REST API, that allows users to demo-trade stocks.
- Learned how to work with SQL databases.

Harvard Online Jul 2020

CS50's Introduction to Computer Science

- Learned how to program using C and Python by completing practical assignments.
- · Learned the fundamentals of computer science.
- Leveraged low-level C programming techniques, including pointer manipulation and dynamic memory management.
- Developed a blog web application using the Flask web development framework.

#### **ADDITIONAL**

Interests: Videogames, technology, soccer, film, science fiction, history, geopolitics, economics

Languages: English

#### **REFERENCES**

Available upon request.